ntis.gov 2019-10-15

# NTIS | Privacy Policy and Security

Privacy Policy and Security

NTIS is committed to protecting your privacy and will collect no personal information about you unless you choose to provide that information. Such information is kept within NTIS although some information may be provided to our agency sources. For products developed under a joint venture, some information may be shared with our joint venture partner.

## Your Rights under the Privacy Act

Information concerning the Privacy Act can be found on the following Web site: [http://www.osec.doc.gov/opog/PrivacyAct/PrivacyAct.html](https://www.ntis.gov/newpage/?url=http://www.osec.doc.gov/opog/PrivacyAct/PrivacyAct.html)

Information concerning Privacy Act requests can be found on the following Web site: [http://www.osec.doc.gov/opog/PrivacyAct/PrivacyAct_requests.html](https://www.ntis.gov/newpage/?url=http://www.osec.doc.gov/opog/PrivacyAct/PrivacyAct_requests.html)

NTIS follows the Department of Commerce's Privacy Policy: [http://www.commerce.gov/privacy-policy](https://www.ntis.gov/newpage/?url=http://www.commerce.gov/privacy-policy)

Department of Commerce Office of Privacy and Open Government: [http://www.commerce.gov/privacy](https://www.ntis.gov/newpage/?url=http://www.commerce.gov/privacy)

Privacy Laws, Policies and Guidance: [http://www.osec.doc.gov/opog/privacy/laws_and_regs.html](https://www.ntis.gov/newpage/?url=http://www.osec.doc.gov/opog/privacy/laws_and_regs.html)

Here is how we handle information about your visit to our site:

  1. If you read or download information, we automatically collect and store the following:
    * Status of the request (was it successful or was there an error?)
    * The date and time you access our site
    * The Internet address of the Web site or domain name of the computer from which you accessed our site
    * The type and version of your Web browser (Netscape, Explorer, etc.) and
    * The operating system (Windows, Mac, Unix, etc.) of the machine running the Web browser
  2. If you send us an e-mail, we will only use it to respond to your message or to provide you ongoing information if you request it.
  3. If you purchase a product on-line, we collect personal information required to support the purchasing of products, including names, addresses, telephone and fax numbers and e-mail addresses.
  4. We collect no personally identifiable information about you when you visit our site unless you choose to provide that information to us. For the protection of users of our Web sites, we have safeguards in place to identify and prevent unauthorized attempts to access or cause harm to information and systems.

## NTIS Hosted Systems Privacy Impact Analysis (PIA) Documentation

## NTIS Hosted Systems System of Records Notice

## Contacting NTIS Privacy Office

Please direct Privacy related complaints, concerns, or questions to [privacy@ntis.gov](mailto:privacy@ntis.gov)

## Links

Our Website has links to many other federal agencies. In a few cases, we link to private organizations with their permission. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site.

## Contacting DOC Senior Agency Official for Privacy

## Third-Party Social Networking

You may be able to access third-party social networks, such as Facebook or Twitter, from the NTIS website. For example, when you Like or Share one of our posts, that post may appear on your Facebook page. Please note that these websites have their own set of information practices and privacy policies and NTIS is not responsible for the information you choose to submit in these forums. NTIS will identify any third-party vendor, website or application that is used to assist the agency for web measurement and customization technology.

See [OMB Memorandum M-10-23, Guidance for Agency Use of Third-Party Websites and Applications](https://www.ntis.gov/newpage/?url=https://www.whitehouse.gov/omb/assets/memoranda_2010/m10-23.pdf) (June 25, 2010) for more information.

## Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)

The Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), 16 CFR Part 312, requires operators of web sites directed to children under age 13, and operators that have actual knowledge of collecting or maintaining personal information from children under 13, to obtain verifiable consent from parents prior to the collection, use, or disclosure of personal information from children. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under age 13 on our web site.

For more information regarding COPPA please visit the Federal Trade Commission’s [Children’s Privacy webpage.](https://www.ntis.gov/newpage/?url=https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/privacy-and-security/children%27s-privacy)

## Security

Shopping online at NTIS is safe and secure. Our secure server software (SSL) is the industry standard and among the best software available today for secure commerce transactions. It encrypts all of your personal information, including credit card or deposit account number, name, and address, so that it cannot be read as the information travels over the Internet.

## Cookies

“Cookies” are small bits of text that are either used for the duration of a session (“session cookies”) or saved on a user's hard drive in order to identify that user, or information about that user, the next time the user logs on the a Web site (“persistent cookies”). This Web site does not use persistent cookies or any other persistent tracking technology. Per-session cookies are used to store information only within a session. These cookies are cached only while a user is visiting the Web server issuing the per-session cookie and are deleted from the cache when the user closes the session. These cookies allow us to provide features such as storing items in your shopping cart. No other site can request this information nor can NTIS track your usage of other sites. If you turn your browser's cookie option off, you can still use most of the features on our site, however, you will not be able to review more than one search results page and you will not be able to order anything with our on-line order processing system. You may still use portions of the website and may order using our telephone sales number.

## Copyright Policy

Some of the materials provided by NTIS are subject to copyrights owned by private parties therefore these may not be copied or distributed without permission of the copyright owner. NTIS cannot grant permission for further use.

To understand if fair use may be applicable, go to [http://cendi.dtic.mil/publications/00-3copyright.html](https://www.ntis.gov/newpage/?url=http://cendi.dtic.mil/publications/00-3copyright.html)

Page Last Updated: June 7, 2017
